Register of the Better Homes in America Records
Hoover Institution Archives
- Correspondence, 1922-1935. (Box 11-22)
  - The Spur, 1925 (Folder 21: 28)
  - Stuck and Sons, 1926 (Folder 21: 29)
  - Successful Farming, 1928 (Folder 21: 30)
  - The Survey (New York), 1926-1927 (Folder 21: 31)
  - Tax Facts, 1924 (Folder 21: 32)
  - Teal, Marion, 1927-1928 (Folder 21: 33)
  - Tee Stone Corporation, 1927-1928 (Folder 21: 34)
  - Tennessee Good Roads Association, 1924 (Folder 21: 35)
  - Thermolator Corporation, 1927 (Folder 21: 36)
  - Thompson, J. Walter Company, 1927 (Folder 21: 37)
  - United Electric Company, 1924 (Folder 21: 38)
  - United States. Department of Agriculture, 1934 (Box-folder 22: 1)
  - United States. Department of Commerce, 1924-1933 (Folder 22: 2)
  - United States. Department of Labor, 1930-1932 (Folder 22: 3)
  - United States. Department of the Interior. Bureau of Education, 1930-1932 (Folder 22: 4)
  - United States Gypsum Company, 1926 (Folder 22: 5)
  - United States Radium Corporation, 1924 (Folder 22: 6)
  - Universal Gypsum and Lime Company, 1926 (Folder 22: 7)
  - Universal Portland Cement Company, 1924 (Folder 22: 8)
  - Universal Sanitary Manufacturing Company, 1926 (Folder 22: 9)
  - Van Guilder System Concrete Building, Inc., 1926 (Folder 22: 10)
  - Van Loan, Anna, 1932-1933 (Folder 22: 11)
  - The Warren Latch Key, 1930 (Folder 22: 12)
  - Washington Committee on Housing, 1934 (Folder 22: 13)
  - The Weekly Retrospect, 1924 (Folder 22: 14)
  - The Welfare Council of New York, 1933-1935 (Folder 22: 15)
  - Western Horticulture Gardens and Homes, 1928 (Folder 22: 16)
  - The Woman Citizen, 1925-1926 (Folder 22: 17)
- Financial Records, 1924-1935. (Box 22-24)
  Audits, cancelled checks, correspondence, office summaries, proposed budgets of the Financial Department. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Audits, 1924-1932 (Folder 22: 18)
  - Cancelled checks
    - 1931 December - 1932 April (Folder 22: 19)
    - 1932 (Box 23)
      - May-September (Folder 23: 1)
      - October-December (Folder 23: 2)
  - Check stubs
    - 1929-1931 (Folder 23: 3)
    - 1932-1933 (Folder 23: 4)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 24: 1)
  - Correspondence, 1928-1935 (Folder 24: 2)
  - Office summaries, 1924-1932 (Folder 24: 3)
  - Proposed budgets to cover financial needs of Better Homes in America, 1925-1929 (Folder 24: 4)
- Publicity File, 1922-1935. (Box 24-33)
  Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, reports, printed matter and other materials relating to publicity operations of the BHA. Arranged alphabetically by subject. See also Publications/Correspondence with publishers
  - General
    - General
      - 1922-1924 (Folder 24: 5)
      - 1925 (Folder 24: 6)
      - 1927-1930 (Box-folder 25: 1)
    - Correspondence
      - General
        - 1924-1927 (Folder 25: 2)
        - 1928-1929 (Folder 25: 3)
        - 1929-1933 (Folder 25: 4)
      - Christian Science Monitor, 1924-1929 (Folder 25: 5)
      - New York Herald Tribune, 1928-1931 (Folder 25: 6)
      - New York Times, 1924-1928 (Folder 25: 7)
      - Radio station WMAL, 1927-1930 (Folder 25: 8)
      - Radio station WRC, 1927 (Folder 25: 9)
      - Washington Post, 1924 (Folder 25: 10)
      - Western Newspaper Union, 1925 (Box-folder 26: 1)
      - Wilkinson, Lupton A.
        - 1924 (Folder 26: 2)
        - 1925 (Folder 26: 3)
      - The Woman's Home Companion, 1924-1932 (Folder 26: 4)
    - Press releases (syndicated series), n.d. (Folder 26: 5)
    - Radio broadcasts, 1925-1930 (Folder 26: 6-7)
    - Reports, 1925-1927 (Folder 26: 8)
  - Campaigns (Box 27)
    - General
      - General
        - 1922 (Folder 27: 1)
        - 1923 (Folder 27: 2-6)
        - 1924 (Folder 27: 7)
        - 1925 (Folder 27: 8)
        - 1926-1927 (Folder 27: 9)
        - 1928 (Folder 27: 10)
        - 1929 (Folder 28: 1-5)
        - 1930 (Folder 28: 6)
        - 1931 (Folder 28: 7-9)
        - 1931 (Box-folder 29: 1)
        - 1932 (Folder 29: 2)
        - 1933 (Folder 29: 3)
        - 1934 (Folder 29: 4)
        - 1935 (Folder 29: 5)
      - Endorsements and statements of cooperation
        - 1925 (Folder 29: 6)
        - 1926 (Folder 29: 7)
        - 1927 (Folder 29: 8)
        - 1928 (Folder 29: 9)
      - Form letters (Folder 29: 10-11)
      - Form letters (Box-folder 30: 1)
      - Home improvement summaries, 1932-1933 (Folder 30: 2)
      - Press releases, 1924-1931 (Folder 30: 3)
      - Questionnaires (Folder 30: 4)
      - Report summaries of local chairmen, 1929 (Folder 30: 5-6)
      - Reports
        - General ("special reports")
          - 1923 (Folder 30: 7)
          - 1924 (Folder 30: 8)
        - White Country, Arkansas, 1931 (Folder 30: 9)
    - Better Homes Week, Pulaski County, Arkansas (Box 31)
      - 1929 (Folder 31: 1)
      - 1930 (Folder 31: 2)
    - Chairmen
      - General, 1928 (Folder 31: 3)
      - Appointments, 1933 (Folder 31: 4)
    - Delaware Better Homes Committee, 1925-1933 (Folder 31: 5)
    - District of Columbia, 1928-1930 (Folder 31: 6)
    - Eastern States Exposition, 1932 (Folder 31: 7)
    - Home management specialists, 1933 (Folder 31: 8)
    - Periodicals participating in campaign efforts, 1924-1932
      - A (Folder 31: 9)
      - B (Box-folder 32: 1)
      - C (Folder 32: 2)
      - D (Folder 32: 3)
      - E (Folder 32: 4)
      - F (Folder 32: 5)
      - G (Folder 32: 6)
    - Prize awards
      - 1923-1932 (Folder 32: 7)
      - 1932 (Folder 32: 8)
      - 1933 (Folder 32: 9)
    - Roadside marketing (Wayside Stand) (Folder 32: 10)
  - Exhibits
    - General, 1923-1933 (Folder 32: 11)
    - Planning, 1924-1930 (Folder 32: 12)
  - Exhibits and fairs, 1924-1930 (Box-folder 33: 1)
  - National planning - United States, 1925-1932 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Purpose of Better Homes in America, n.d. (Folder 33: 3)
  - Radio broadcasting, 1923-1933
    - General (Folder 33: 4)
    - Radio stations
      - WEAF (Folder 33: 5)
      - WBAL (Folder 33: 6)
      - WJZ (Folder 33: 7)
  - Miscellany, 1926-1932 (Folder 33: 8)
- Publications File, 1924-1937. (Box 33-39)
  Articles and printed matter published by BHA staff and correspondence with publishers of BHA articles. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - Articles by the Better Homes in America staff published in various publications, 1926-1932
    - General (Folder 33: 9-12)
    - Home Improvement, 1937 (Box-folder 34: 1)
    - Home Information Service, 1936 (Folder 34: 2-3)
  - Correspondence with publishers of articles by the Better Homes in America staff, 1924-1934
    - Books
      - Better Homes Manual, 1931-1934 (Folder 34: 4-6)
      - Care and Repair of the Home, 1930-1932 (Folder 34: 7)
      - Home and Community Song Book (Box 35)
        - 1927-1929 (Folder 35: 1)
        - 1930-1931 (Folder 35: 2)
        - 1931-1932 (Folder 35: 3)
    - Periodicals
      - American Building Association News
        - 1925-1928 (Folder 35: 4)
        - 1928-1929 (Folder 35: 5)
        - 1930-1931 (Folder 35: 6)
        - 1931-1933 (Box-folder 36: 1)
      - The American City, 1923-1932 (Folder 36: 2)
      - Better Homes and Gardens, 1927-1930 (Folder 36: 3)
      - Child Welfare
        - 1925-1930 (Folder 36: 4-5)
        - 1930 (Folder 36: 6)
        - 1931-1932 (Box-folder 37: 1)
        - 1932-1934 (Folder 37: 2)
      - Children, A Magazine for Parents, 1926-1930 (Folder 37: 3)
      - The Community Builder, 1925-1928 (Folder 37: 4)
      - The Country Gentleman, 1924-1932 (Folder 37: 5)
      - Country Life, 1925-1929 (Folder 37: 6)
      - The Farm Journal, 1924-1932 (Folder 37: 7)
      - The Farmer's Wife, 1925-1934 (Folder 37: 8)
      - The Forecast, 1925-1929 (Folder 37: 9)
      - Good Housekeeping, 1924-1930 (Folder 37: 10)
      - High School Teacher, 1927-1931 (Folder 37: 11)
      - Home Building, 1924-1928 (Folder 37: 12)
      - House and Garden, 1925-1927 (Folder 37: 13)
      - House Beautiful, 1924-1932 (Folder 37: 14)
      - Household Magazine, 1925-1933 (Folder 37: 15)
      - Independent Woman, 1925-1926 (Folder 37: 16)
      - Industrial Arts Magazine, 1927-1928 (Box-folder 38: 1)
      - Journal of Home Economics, 1924-1932 (Folder 38: 2)
      - McCalls Magazine, 1924-1930 (Folder 38: 3)
      - The Modern Priscilla, 1926-1928 (Folder 38: 4)
      - Outdoors Pictorial, 1924-1925 (Folder 38: 5)
      - Pictorial Review, 1933 (Folder 38: 6)
      - Progressive Farmer, 1925-1932 (Folder 38: 7)
      - The Red Cross Courier, 1926-1927 (Folder 38: 8)
      - Save the Surface, 1924-1926 (Folder 38: 9)
      - The Small Home, 1930-32 (Folder 38: 10)
      - The Southern Planter, 1927-1931 (Folder 38: 11)
      - Southern Ruralist, 1925-1930 (Folder 38: 12)
      - The Southern Workman, 1924-1932 (Folder 38: 13)
  - Inventories of publications on hand, 1929-1932 (Folder 38: 14)
  - Publications issued by Better Homes in America (Box 39)
    - America's Little House, 1934 (Folder 39: 1)
    - Guidebook for Better Homes Campaigns, 1925-1932 (Folder 39: 2)
    - How to Furnish the Small Home, 1924 April (Folder 39: 3)
  - Subject file
    - Copyright issues, 1923-1933 (Folder 39: 4-5)
    - Garden pamphlet publication planning, 1924-1930 (Folder 39: 6)
    - Miscellany, 1924-1930 (Folder 39: 7)
- Subject File, 1924-1935. (Box 39-41)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, clippings and other material, arranged alphabetically by subject
  - American Homemakers, Inc., 1926-1932 (Folder 39: 8)
  - Approved Wayside Stations, Inc., 1926-1933 (Box-folder 40: 1)
  - Architectural Merit Prizes, 1925 (Folder 40: 2)
  - Commercialism - United States, 1925-1933 (Folder 40: 3)
  - Crane, Ross, 1930 (Folder 40: 4)
  - Delaware - Report of the Housing Commission of the State of Delaware, 1932 (Folder 40: 5)
  - Girl Scout Little House, 1925 (Folder 40: 6)
  - Home Loan Bank Bill, 1932 July
    - General (Folder 40: 7)
    - Clippings (Folder 40: 8-10)
    - Clippings (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Housing and recreation - Bibliographies, n.d. (Folder 41: 2)
  - Log cabins, 1927-1929 (Folder 41: 3)
  - National Conference on Outdoor Recreation, 1925 (Folder 41: 4)
  - National Public Housing Conference, 1933 November 25 (Folder 41: 5)
  - National Recreation Association, 1931-1932 (Folder 41: 6)
  - Playground and Recreation Association of America, 1930-1932 (Folder 41: 7)
  - Purdue Research Foundation - Proceedings of the Homes Conference, 1935 June 1 (Folder 41: 8)
  - Real estate - United States, 1929-1932 (Folder 41: 9)
  - Recreation - United States (Folder 41: 10-11)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1932-1934 (Folder 41: 12)
  - Rockefeller Foundation - Review for 1928 (Folder 41: 13)
  - Miscellany, 1925-1933 (Folder 41: 14)
- Clippings, 1920-1933. (Box 42-56)
  Newspaper and periodical clippings arranged alphabetically by subject
  - General (Box 42)
    - 1921-1923 (Folder 42: 1)
    - 1922-1923 (Folder 42: 2)
    - 1923 (Folder 42: 3)
    - 1923-1924 (Folder 42: 4)
    - 1923-1924 (Box-folder 43: 1)
    - 1923-1930 (Folder 43: 2)
    - 1924 (Folder 43: 3-5)
    - 1924 (Box-folder 44: 1-3)
    - 1925-1926 (Folder 44: 4-5)
    - 1926 (Box-folder 45: 1-3)
    - 1926-1927 (Folder 45: 4)
    - 1927 (Folder 45: 5)
    - 1927 (Box-folder 46: 1)
    - 1928 (Folder 46: 2)
    - 1933 (Folder 46: 3)
  - Building costs
    - General, 1920-1933 (Folder 46: 4-5)
    - Cost of a six-room frame house, 1923-1933 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - City planning
    - General, 1923-1931 (Folder 47: 2-5)
    - Washington, D.C., 1826-1933 (Box-folder 48: 1-3)
  - Conferences, 1922 (Folder 48: 4)
  - Home building
    - 1921-1924 (Folder 48: 5)
    - 1924-1925 (Box-folder 49: 1)
    - 1925-1927 (Folder 49: 2)
    - 1927-1929 (Folder 49: 3)
    - 1929-1930 (Folder 49: 4)
    - 1931-1933 (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - Home financing
    - 1922-1925 (Folder 50: 2)
    - 1926-1929 (Folder 50: 3)
    - 1930-1932 (Folder 50: 4)
    - 1932 (Folder 50: 5)
  - Home ownership (Box 51)
    - 1926-1929 (Folder 51: 1)
    - 1930-1933 (Folder 51: 2)
  - Hoover, Herbert C.
    - 1922-1932 (Folder 51: 3)
    - 1932 (Folder 51: 4-5)
    - 1932-1933 (Box-folder 52: 1)
  - Housing - United States
    - General
      - 1920-1922 (Folder 52: 2)
      - 1923-1925 (Folder 52: 3)
      - 1925-1927 (Folder 52: 4)
      - 1927-1930 (Box-folder 53: 1)
      - 1930-1933 (Folder 53: 2)
    - Government workers
      - 1925-1926 (Folder 53: 3)
      - 1926 (Folder 53: 4)
  - Labor - United States, 1920-1932 (Folder 53: 5)
  - Master Builder, 1926 (Folder 53: 6)
  - Materials used in construction (Box 54)
    - 1924 (Folder 54: 1)
    - 1924-1927 (Folder 54: 2)
    - 1927-1933 (Folder 54: 3)
  - Mechanics lien law, 1926 (Folder 54: 4)
  - National Conference of Banking and Industrial Committees, 1932 (Folder 54: 5)
  - President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1931-1932 (Folder 54: 6)
  - President's Conference on Home Building and Home Ownership, 1931-1932 (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Public health - United States, 1931-1932 (Folder 55: 2)
  - Real estate - United States, 1923-1933 (Folder 55: 3)
  - Standardization - United States, 1922-1932 (Folder 55: 4)
  - Wages, 1926 (Folder 55: 5)
  - White House Conference on Child Health and Protection, 1931-1932 (Folder 55: 6)
  - Zoning
    - 1921-1922 (Folder 55: 7)
    - 1922-1924 (Box-folder 56: 1)
    - 1924 (Folder 56: 2)
    - 1927-1929 (Folder 56: 3)
    - 1929-1933 (Folder 56: 4)
- Scrapbooks, 1926-1931. (Box 57-60)
  Scrapbooks containing correspondence, memoranda, clippings, printed matter, and photographs, collected by the BHA staff. Arranged alphabetically by subject
  - Adobe construction, 1927-1928 (Folder 57: 1)
  - Better Homes Week
    - Boston, 1931 (Folder 57: 2-3)
    - Santa Barbara
      - 1926 (Folder 57: 4)
      - 1926 (Box-folder 58: 1)
      - 1927 (Folder 58: 2-4)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 59: 1)
      - 1929 (Folder 59: 2-3)
      - 1930 (Folder 59: 4-5)
      - 1931 (Folder 59: 6)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 60: 1-2)
- Oversize Material, 1922-1934. (Box 61-70)
  Albums and scrapbooks containing correspondence, reports, memoranda, photographs and printed matter, collected by the BHA staff. Arranged alphabetically by subject. See also Scrapbooks.
  - America's Little House, 1934 October (2 scrapbooks) (Box 61-70)
  - Better Homes Week
    - General
      - 1922 (Folder 61: 1)
      - 1923 (Folder 61A: 2)
      - 1923 (Box-folder 62: 1)
    - Greenville, South Carolina (Box 63)
      - 1929 (Folder 63: 1)
      - 1930 (Box 64)
        - Volume I (Folder 64: 1)
        - Volume II (Box-folder 65: 1)
    - Santa Barbara County (Box 66)
      - 1925 (Folder 66: 1)
      - 1927 (Folder 66: 2)
      - 1928 (Box-folder 67: 1)
      - 1929 (Box-folder 68: 1)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 69: 1)
      - 1931 (Folder 69A: 2)
      - 1931 (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - Campaign in Washington, D.C., 1924 (Folder 70: 2)
- Photographs, 1929-1934. (Box 71)
  11 prints and an album containing 140 prints depicting structures and people engaged in BHA operations
  - 11 prints depicting interiors and exteriors of model homes, mothers with infants, a doctor examining an infant, a group of teenagers playing with puppets on strings and examining a painting exhibit, 1929-1934 (Folder 71: 1)
  - One album containing 140 prints depicting interiors and exteriors of model homes and various groups of individuals, 1929 (Folder 71: 2)